Ellis, A. D. & Son Records 6493
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
A. D. Ellis & Son Records
1911-1934
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
A. D. Ellis & Son
6493
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, records (documents).
Records include payroll (From Ellis, Converse & Co.), outgoing correspondence, notebook of orders, weaving drafts & counts, including price lists and costs, and 2 folders of miscellaneous drafts. Correspondents include H. & W.H. Lewis, Laidlaw Co., & Lynx Corp., all of New York City. Includes Navy contracts & government bids, 1917-1934.
11022013
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, September 05, 2019
EAD encoding:
Marcie Farwell, October 09, 2019
Biographical / Historical
A.D. Ellis & Son, located in Monson, MA was a Woolen manufacturer. Established in 1872 to produce fine cassimeres, it was one of several mills belonging to Dwight W. Ellis. Around 1875, Arthur D. Ellis became a partner. Over time the mill manufactured broadcloth, billiard cloth, uniform cloth & jerseys. By the late 1930's auto & uniform cloth were its only products.
The company closed in 1961.
Scope and Contents
Records include general outgoing correspondence, 1872-1887, 1899-1901; and correspondence concerning sales, etc., 1915-1934. Correspondents include H. & W.H. Lewis, Laidlaw Company, and Lynx Corporation, all of New York City. Collection also includes Navy contracts and government bids, 1917-1934; and payroll ledgers containing rent and board deductions and amounts produced by weavers; these are labelled Ellis, Converse & Co. Also included are weaving drafts and counts, plus price lists and costs, 1910-1916
Custodial History
American Textile History Museum Collection, gift of A.D. Ellis & Son.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Business records; Contracts; Payrolls; Price lists; Textile industry; Weaving; Woolen and worsted manufacture; Labor records; Weaving drafts; Wool industry; Monson (Mass.); United States; Converse, E. Julius.; Ellis, Arthur D.; Ellis, Dwight W.; A. D. Ellis & Sons; Converse, Ellis & Company; D.W. Ellis & Sons Woolen Mill (Monson, Mass.); Laidlaw Company (New York, N.Y.); Lynx Corporation (New York, N.Y.)
11022013
- Production Correspondence: H.H. Lewis, 1915-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Production Correspondence: Laidlow Co. Inc., 1921-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Navy Contracts and Government Bids, 1917-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Navy contracts and Government bids ((2 cloth samples/wool for earliest mens uniform), 1917-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence in Lynx Corporation, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Weaving Drafts and 3.6 counts (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Weaving Drafts and Counts (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Weaving Drafts and Counts (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Weaving Drafts and Counts, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Auto Drafts" Weaving Drafts (Box 1, Folder 10)